⦅知ってますか？
Did you know?
The distance from your eye level to the horizon
高い[たかい]:high/tall|expensive, 見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife), 水平[すいへい]:level/horizontality, 線[せん]:line|line (e.g. telephone line)|ray (e.g. X-ray)||, 距離[きょり]:distance/range
人の目の高さから見える
水平線までの距離は
約[やく]:approximately|promise|shortening|, キロメートル:kilometer/kilometre
約４ｷﾛﾒｰﾄﾙなんですよ｡
is around four kilometers.
Do the people who live around here
have a habit of talking to total strangers?
(咲太)このへんの人って
見ず知らずの人に
突然[とつぜん]:abrupt/sudden/unexpected, 話しかける[はなしかける]:to address (someone)/to accost a person|to begin to talk
突然 話しかけたり
するもんなんですか？
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
あっ もしかして 私のこと
ﾍﾝな人だと思ってます？
Wait, do you think I'm some weirdo?
Nah, I just think you're annoying.
ウザい:annoying/noisy|strict
いえ ｳｻﾞい人だと
思ってるだけです｡
You can't say that to a high school girl.
女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student, 禁句[きんく]:taboo word
それ 女子高生には禁句です｡
There are three taboo words:
annoying, clueless, and lame.
ウザい:annoying/noisy|strict, ダサい:uncool/unsophisticated/unfashionable, 空気[くうき]:air|mood|someone with no presence, 読む[よむ]:to read|to count|to guess, 三[さん, み]:three|tri-, 三[サン]:three, 大[おお]:big/large, 大[だい]:the large part of|big|approximate size||, 禁句[きんく]:taboo word
ｳｻﾞい ﾀﾞｻい 空気読めないは
三大禁句｡
少年[しょうねん]:boy/juvenile/young boy, ずいぶん:very/extremely|contemptible, さぐれる:to feel around for/to fumble for|to investigate
少年は ずいぶんと
やさぐれているようですけど
You seem to have lost your way, kiddo.
Did something bad happen?
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
何か嫌なことでも
あったんですか？
私は 牧之原翔子です｡
I'm Makinohara Shouko.
サービスエリア:service area (usu. an area off a highway to buy gasoline, etc. for vehicles), 大空[おおぞら]:heavens/firmament/sky, 翔る[かける]:to soar/to fly|to run
牧之原ｻｰﾋﾞｽｴﾘｱの牧之原に
大空を翔る子の翔子｡
Shouko with the character for flying, like in the sky,
and Makinohara from "Makinohara Service Area."
少年[しょうねん]:boy/juvenile/young boy
少年の名前は？⦆
What's your name?
Good morning, Onii-chan.
おはようございます:good morning, お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
(かえで)おはようございます
お兄ちゃん｡
Kaede, how many times must I tell you
to quit sneaking into my bed?
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), 何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?
かえで 何度も言ってるが
ベッド:bed, 潜り込む[もぐりこむ]:to slip into/to crawl into (under)|to sneak into, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, なさる:to do
僕のﾍﾞｯﾄﾞに潜り込むのは
やめなさい｡
Why? Because you might awaken to a forbidden love?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 禁断[きんだん]:prohibition/interdiction|forbidden, 愛[あい]:love/affection|attachment, 愛[まな]:beloved/dear, 目覚める[めざめる]:to wake up|to awaken to (instinct, ability, perception, etc.)|to come to one's senses, しまう:to finish/to stop|to close (a business, etc.)
お兄ちゃんが禁断の愛に
目覚めてしまうからですか？
Hell no. It's just warm enough already
without you in there.
ただただ:absolutely/only, 暑い[あつい]:hot (weather, etc.)/warm, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit
違うな ただただ暑いから
やめてほしいんだ｡
August 2nd
The girl who appeared before me that day
along with the abandoned cat
捨て猫[すてねこ]:abandoned (stray) cat, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 現れる[あらわれる]:to appear/to come in sight|to be expressed (e.g. emotions), 少女[しょうじょ, おとめ]:little girl/maiden|female between 17 and 20 years old (ritsuryo period)
《あの日 捨て猫と一緒に
僕の前に現れた少女は
出会う[であう]:to meet (by chance)|to meet (e.g. of rivers, highways, etc.)|to emerge and engage (an enemy)
僕が２年前に出会った
had the same name as my first love,
the high school girl I met two years ago.
初恋[はつこい]:first love/puppy love, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 女子高生[じょしこうせい]:female high-school student, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
初恋相手の女子高生と
同じ名前だった》
My name is Makinohara Shouko.
⦅牧之原翔子といいます⦆
She had the same name...
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
《同じ名前だったんだけど…》
本人[ほんにん]:the person himself
《本人は 僕のことなど
何も知らず
but she didn't recognize me at all,
何事[なにごと]:what|nothing (with neg. verb)|something or other, 起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents), 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 週間[しゅうかん]:weeks (period of), 過ぎる[すぎる]:to pass through|to pass (i.e. of time)|to have expired||, 過ぎる[よぎる]:to go by/to cross/to pass by
何事も起きないまま
夏休みは２週間過ぎた》
and an uneventful two weeks of summer break flew by.
There, there.
はやて:gale/strong wind/swift wind
よしよし いい子にしてましたか？
はやて｡
Have you been a good boy, Hayate?
Oh...
猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat, はやて:gale/strong wind/swift wind, 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
《あっ 猫の名前は
はやてに決まった｡
The cat was named Hayate. He and Nasuno
are now Tohoku Shinkansen buddies.
東北[とうほく, ひがしきた]:north-east|Tohoku (northernmost six prefectures of Honshu), つながり:connection/link/relationship
なすのとは東北つながり》
I'm sorry.
なさる:to do, 引き取る[ひきとる]:to take over|to take charge of|to retire to a private place, ながら:while/during|while
ごめんなさい 引き取りたいと
言っておきながら
I said I wanted to keep him, but I haven't been able to bring it up to my parents.
なかなか:very/considerably|by no means (with negative verb), 両親[りょうしん, ふたおや]:parents/both parents, 出す[だす]:to take out|to put out|to submit (e.g. thesis)||
なかなか両親に言い出せなくて｡
It's fine. He can stay with us for the time being.
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 預かる[あずかる]:to look after|to take charge of|to reserve (judgment), 平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right
しばらくは うちで
預かっておくから 平気だよ｡
喜ぶ[よろこぶ]:to be delighted|to congratulate|to gratefully accept
なすのも喜んでるし｡
牧之原さんも ここで
Nasuno seems to enjoy the company.
And you can practice how to take care of a cat here.
猫[ねこ, ネコ]:cat|shamisen|geisha||, 猫[ねこま]:cat, 世話[せわ]:looking after/help/aid, 練習[れんしゅう]:practice/practising
猫の世話の練習をしておけばいい｡
はい｡
Thank you.
Onii-chan, are you someone who prefers much younger little sisters?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 若い[わかい]:young|immature|low (number)
お兄ちゃんは 妹は若い子のほうが
いい人ですか？
清楚[せいそ]:neat and clean/tidy/trim, 礼儀[れいぎ]:manners/courtesy/etiquette, 正しい[ただしい]:right/correct|proper, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
清楚で礼儀正しい妹が
いい人ですか？
Do you prefer refined and
well-mannered little sisters?
What's with those questions?
質問[しつもん]:question/inquiry/enquiry
なんだ その質問は｡
今 かえでは
I'm currently facing the crisis of a lifetime!
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), 史上[しじょう]:in history/ever/historical, 最大[さいだい]:biggest/greatest/largest, ピンチ:crisis/tough spot/predicament
かえで史上最大のﾋﾟﾝﾁなんです｡
I need to master the way of the
little sister as quickly as possible!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, 道[みち]:road|distance|the way (of proper conduct, etc.)||, 道[どう]:road|way|Buddhist teachings||, 極める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||, 極める[きわめる]:to carry to extremes/to go to the end of something|to investigate thoroughly, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
１日も早く 妹道を
極めないといけないんです｡
I'm someone who's perfectly content with having you as my little sister.
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
僕は 妹は かえで１人いれば
いい人だな｡
Th-Then...
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister
で では 翔子さんは
お兄ちゃんにとって
What is Shouko-san to you?
何なんですか？
何なんだろうな｡
What, indeed?
お姉さん[おねえさん]:elder sister|(vocative) young lady|miss (referring to a waitress, etc.)||
牧之原さん お姉さんは
いないんだよね？
Makinohara-san, you don't have an older sister, right?
一人っ子[ひとりっこ]:(an) only child
はい 一人っ子ですから｡
That's right. I'm an only child.
Any cousins who look a lot like you?
親戚[しんせき]:relative/relation/kin, 似る[にる]:to resemble/to look like|to be similar (in status, condition, etc.)
親戚に よく似た人は？
いないと思います｡
I don't think so.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
ﾊｧ… やっぱり
双葉に相談しとくかな｡
I guess I really should talk to Futaba about this.
Azusagawa
What is it, Azusagawa?
(理央)なに？ 梓川｡
Episode 7: Youth Is a Paradox
Futaba?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 髪[かみ]:hair (on the head), おろす:to sell wholesale|to grate (e.g. vegetables), おろす:to take down (e.g. flag)/to launch (e.g. boat)|to drop off (a passenger from a vehicle), 暑い[あつい]:hot (weather, etc.)/warm
双葉？
髪おろしてると暑いんだよ｡
It's too hot to wear my hair down.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, コンタクト:contact
ﾒｶﾞﾈをしてないのはｺﾝﾀｸﾄだから｡
And I'm wearing contacts, so no glasses.
制服[せいふく]:uniform, 学校[がっこう]:school
なんで制服？
このあと学校｡
Why the uniform?
I'm on my way to school.
バイト:work (esp. part time or casual)
国見なら ﾊﾞｲﾄだからいないぞ｡
Kunimi won't be there. He's got work.
部員[ぶいん]:staff/member (club, society, etc.), 科学[かがく]:science, 部[ぶ]:department (in an organization)|club|part||, 活動[かつどう]:action/activity|movie (esp. during the silent movie period), 実績を残す[じっせきをのこす]:to accomplish something/to leave a mark/to make an impression
部員１人の科学部は
活動実績を残しておかないと
I'm the only member of the science club.
It'll be shut down if I'm not productive.
即[そく]:instantly/immediately|that is (to say), 廃部[はいぶ]:club disbandment
即廃部になるんだよ｡
So, what did you want to talk about?
用事[ようじ]:tasks/things to do/errand
で 梓川の用事っていうのは？
あ ああ…｡
O-Oh, the thing is...
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|
実は… 牧之原翔子に会った｡
I met Makinohara Shouko.
Your first love? She was real, huh?
初恋[はつこい]:first love/puppy love, 実在[じつざい]:reality/existence
梓川の初恋の人？
実在したんだ｡
Shockingly, she'd turned into a middle-school first-year.
しかも:moreover/furthermore|nevertheless, 驚く[おどろく]:to be surprised/to be astonished, 中学[ちゅうがく]:middle school/junior high school, 年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year
しかも 驚いたことに
中学１年生になってた｡
Have you lost your mind?
正気[しょうき]:sanity/consciousness/soberness, 正気[せいき]:true character/true heart/true spirit, 残念[ざんねん]:deplorable/bad luck/regret, ながら:while/during|while
梓川 正気？
残念ながら｡
Unfortunately not.
似る[にる]:to resemble/to look like|to be similar (in status, condition, etc.), 同姓[どうせい]:same surname, 同名[どうめい, どうみょう]:same name|homonym, 別人[べつじん, べつにん]:different person/someone else/changed man
よく似た同姓同名の
別人なんじゃないの？
It must be a different girl who just looks like her
and has the same name.
I hear everyone in the world has two doppelgangers.
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
世界には 同じ顔をした人間が
３人いるらしいよ｡
That's just a common myth.
都市[とし]:town/city/municipal, 伝説[でんせつ]:tradition/legend/folklore
んなの よくある都市伝説だろ｡
そうだね よくある都市伝説…｡
Yeah, just a common myth.
実害[じつがい]:real harm
でもさ 今のところ そっちは
実害ないんでしょ？
Anyway, no harm's been done so far, right?
I guess not.
まあ ないな｡
だったら いいんじゃない？
Then don't worry about it.
Oh, is there a fireworks show happening somewhere?
花火[はなび]:fireworks
今日 どっかで花火やるんだな｡
Tonight, at Chigasaki.
茅ヶ崎が今日｡
去年[きょねん, こぞ]:last year, 花火[はなび]:fireworks, 大会[たいかい]:convention/tournament/mass meeting
そういや 去年 行ったよな
花火大会 国見と３人で｡
That reminds me, we went to one with Kunimi last year.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 私服[しふく]:civilian clothes/plain clothes|plainclothes police officer, 浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
あのとき 双葉 私服だったよな
浴衣 着てくればよかったのに｡
And you dressed normally for it.
You should've worn a yukata.
どうして 私が梓川のために
Why should I have to wear one for you?
They're a massive pain.
面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, いける:to arrange (flowers)/to plant|living, いける:to be good (at)/to go well|to look (taste, etc.) good
そんな面倒なことを
しなくちゃいけないわけ？
見せる[みせる]:to show/to display, どのみち:anyway/anyhow/at any rate, 似合う[にあう]:to suit/to match/to become
国見に見せるためだよ｡
どのみち 私には似合わない｡
To show Kunimi.
I wouldn't look good in one, anyway.
浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 胸[むね, むな]:chest|breasts|heart||, 大きい[おおきい]:big/large/great
浴衣って 胸が大きいと
ﾀﾞﾒなんだっけ？
Does a yukata not go well with big boobs?
That's not what I meant.
意味[いみ]:meaning/significance, 髪型[かみがた]:hair style/coiffure/hairdo, 浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 着る[きる]:to wear (in modern Japanese, from the shoulders down)/to put on|to bear (guilt, etc.)
そういう意味で言ったんじゃない｡
今の髪型で浴衣着たら
I think it'd go pretty great with that hairstyle.
かなり:considerably/fairly/quite
かなりいいと思うけどな｡
Forget it.
バイト:work (esp. part time or casual)
もういい 梓川はﾊﾞｲﾄでしょ
それじゃ｡
You have work, right? See you.
Thanks for hearing me out.
相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion, サンキュ:thank you
相談のってくれてｻﾝｷｭ｡
Did you get even more of a tan?
更に[さらに]:furthermore/again/after all, 日焼け[ひやけ]:sunburn/suntan|becoming discolored from the sun (e.g. paper)
お前 更に日焼けしてないか？
おととい:day before yesterday, 海[うみ, み]:sea/ocean/waters
(国見)おととい
海に行ったせいかも｡
I hit the beach the day before yesterday.
上里と？
そうだけど｡
With Kamisato?
Yeah, why?
God, so annoying.
ウザい:annoying/noisy|strict
ｳﾍｯ ｳｻﾞいな｡
Hey, you have a ridiculously hot girlfriend too.
とんでも:unthinkable/unexpected/outrageous, 美人[びじん]:beautiful woman
咲太だって とんでもなく美人な
彼女がいるだろ｡
One I haven't seen in a week
because she's ridiculously busy.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, とんでも:unthinkable/unexpected/outrageous, 忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless
その麻衣さんは
とんでもなく忙しくて
週間[しゅうかん]:weeks (period of), 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, テレビ:television/TV
この１週間 顔を見てない｡
俺 昨日 ﾃﾚﾋﾞで見たぞ｡
I saw her on TV yesterday.
Rest assured, I see her every day on the TV too.
安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice, テレビ:television/TV, 毎日[まいにち]:every day
安心しろ ﾃﾚﾋﾞでなら
僕も毎日見てる｡
Hello...
おはようございます:good morning
(朋絵)おはようございます…｡
Ack, Senpai!
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe)
ｹﾞｯ 先輩！
かわいい浴衣を
Did you come to show off your cute yukata?
自慢[じまん]:pride/boast, 来週[らいしゅう]:next week, 予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule
自慢しにきたのか？
来週の予定出してないから
I'm just here to submit my
shift request for next week.
出し[だし, ダシ]:dashi (Japanese soup stock made from fish and kelp)|pretext/excuse
出しにきただけだし｡
I must admit, you look nice in one.
浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 似合う[にあう]:to suit/to match/to become, 胸[むね, むな]:chest|breasts|heart||
古賀って 浴衣似合うのな｡
今 胸見て言ったでしょ｡
Did you say that after looking at my chest?
腰[こし, コシ]:back/lower back|body (of hair, noodle, paper, etc.), 腰[ごし]:posture/position/pose, お尻[おしり, オシリ]:bottom/buttocks, バランス:balance, 含める[ふくめる]:to include (in a group or scope)|to instruct|to include (a nuance)||, 発言[はつげん]:statement/remark/observation
腰とお尻のﾊﾞﾗﾝｽも含めたうえでの
発言だ｡
I also took your waist and butt into account before making the observation.
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 帯[おび, たらし]:obi/kimono sash|paper wrapper on books, CDs, etc., 帯[たい]:band (e.g. conduction, valence)/belt (e.g. Van-Allen, asteroid, etc.), どっかり:plunking (down something heavy)/flumping (into a chair), 乗る[のる]:to get on (train, plane, bus, ship, etc.)|to get on (e.g. a footstool)|to reach||
ﾊﾞﾘﾑｶ～！ どうせ 帯に
どっかり乗るような
Now I'm steamin'!
Yeah, yeah, I don't have boobs big enough
to hang over the sash!
立派[りっぱ]:splendid|praiseworthy|legal|, 胸[むね, むな]:chest|breasts|heart||, 寸胴[ずんどう, ずんど]:cylindrical container (pot, vase, etc.)|having no waist (straight body figure, not curvy)|sleeveless (coat etc.)
立派な胸はないですよ！
寸胴ですよ！
And my waist isn't shapely!
いらっしゃる:to come/to go|is (doing)
いらっしゃいま…｡
Welcome—
帰ってくる[かえってくる]:to return/to come back, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future
ﾛｹから帰ってくるの
明日でしたよね？
Weren't you only supposed to come back
from the shoot tomorrow?
ベテラン:person with a lot of experience/old hand/veteran (in a particular field), 役者[やくしゃ]:actor/actress, 現場[げんば, げんじょう]:actual spot/scene|shop floor
(麻衣)ﾍﾞﾃﾗﾝの役者が
多い現場だったし
There were a lot of veteran actors,
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 終わる[おわる]:to finish/to end/to close
私もNG出さないから
早く終わったのよ｡
and I don't need many retakes,
so it ended sooner than expected.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
なるほど で １日でも早く
僕に会いたくて
I see.
And you rushed back because you wanted to see me as soon as possible?
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
帰ってきたんですね｡
うれしいなぁ｡
I'm so chuffed.
なによ それ｡
What's with that tone?
決まり[きまり]:rule|settlement|habit||, 注文[ちゅうもん]:order/request, 注文[ちゅうぶん]:annotation/explanatory note, どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
お決まりでしたら
ご注文をどうぞ｡
If you've decided on your order, I'll take it.
注文[ちゅうもん]:order/request, 注文[ちゅうぶん]:annotation/explanatory note, どうぞ:please/kindly|by all means
ん…｡
ご注文をどうぞ｡
I'll take your order.
すねる:to be peevish/to sulk/to pout
なに すねてるのよ｡
すねてません｡
What are you sulking for?
I'm not sulking.
You clearly are.
すねる:to be peevish/to sulk/to pout
すねてるじゃない｡
誰のせいだと思いますか？
Whose fault do you think that is?
それは その…｡
その？
Uh, well...
Well?
ごめん…｡
Sorry.
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 夢中[むちゅう]:daze/(in a) trance/ecstasy, つきあう:to associate with/to keep company with|to go along with, つきあう:to poke each other/to jab each other, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room, 彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend
仕事に夢中で
つきあって間もない彼氏を
I'm aware I'm being an awful girlfriend
who's neglecting her new boyfriend due to work.
ほったらかしにする:to neglect/to let alone, ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent
ほったらかしにしている
ひどい彼女だってことは
自覚[じかく]:self-consciousness/self-awareness
自覚してる｡
そこまでは思ってないけど…｡
Hey, I don't think you're "awful," but...
詫び[わび]:apology/excuse, 期待[きたい]:expectation/anticipation/hope
けど？
お詫びには期待してます｡
But?
I do expect you to make up for this.
あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
わかった それなりのことは
してあげるから｡
Fine. I'll do something nice for you.
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, 少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
ｴﾛいことでも？
少しくらいならね｡
Even if it's lewd?
A little bit.
許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair), 調子[ちょうし]:tune|vein|condition||
じゃあ 許してあげます｡
調子にのるな｡
I'll forgive you, then.
Don't push your luck.
I'm overjoyed that you came back so early!
早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
早く帰ってきてくれて
すげえうれしいです｡
You should've said that first, stupid.
先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.), なさる:to do
ﾊﾞｰｶ それを先に言いなさい｡
バイト:work (esp. part time or casual), 何時[いつ]:when/how soon, 何時[なんじ, なんどき]:what time?, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
ﾊﾞｲﾄ何時まで？ 待っててあげる｡
When does your shift end? I'll wait.
毎日[まいにち]:every day
彼女 毎日来てるの？
ん？
Has she been coming every day?
初恋[はつこい]:first love/puppy love, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.)
咲太の初恋相手にｿｯｸﾘな
牧之原翔子さん｡
Makinohara Shouko, the girl who looks just like your first love.
気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
来てますよ 気になります？
She has. Does it bother you?
Why would I feel threatened
by a middle-school first-year?
中学[ちゅうがく]:middle school/junior high school, 年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year, 女の子[おんなのこ, おんなのコ]:girl/daughter|young woman, 女の子[めのこ]:woman/girl, 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 嫉妬[しっと]:jealousy/envy, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
中学１年生の女の子相手に
嫉妬なんてするわけないでしょ｡
変わる[かわる]:to change|to move to|to be different
何か変わったことは？
ないですね｡
Anything unusual happen?
Not really.
何かわかったことは？
Figure anything out?
I even talked to Futaba about it, but not a thing.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 相談[そうだん]:consultation/discussion
双葉にも相談してみたんですけど
何にも｡
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc., 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, イチャイチャ:flirt/make out
そんな話より 僕は麻衣さんと
もっとｲﾁｬｲﾁｬしたいなぁ｡
Rather than talk about that,
I wanna be all lovey-dovey with you.
せっかく:stone burial chamber, せっかく:with trouble/at great pains|rare, 久しぶり[ひさしぶり]:a long time (since the last time)/it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you), 会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association
せっかく久しぶりに会えたのに｡
We haven't seen each other in a while.
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
あとで好きなだけしてあげるから｡
We can be as lovey-dovey as you want later.
What? I'd rather start now.
え～ 今がいいなぁ｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
あっ あれ 双葉さんじゃない？
Hey, isn't that Futaba-san?
こんなとこで何してんだ あいつ？
What is she doing here?
I've never been in a net café before.
ネットカフェ:Internet cafe/net cafe, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
私 ﾈｯﾄｶﾌｪって初めて｡
これじゃ どこだか
わからないわね｡
We can't find her like this.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, スマホ:smartphone/smart phone, 貸す[かす]:to lend/to loan|to rent out
麻衣さん ｽﾏﾎ貸して｡
Let me borrow your phone, Mai-san.
Hello?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
[℡](理央)はい｡
双葉 僕だ｡
Futaba, it's me.
Why are you calling me from a cell phone?
ケータイ:something carried (in the hand)/handheld/portable, 番号[ばんごう]:number/series of digits, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
[℡]なんで 梓川が
ｹｰﾀｲの番号からかけてくるわけ？
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 借りる[かりる]:to borrow/to have a loan|to rent, のろけ:speaking fondly of a loved one
麻衣さんに借りてる｡
[℡]のろけなら よそでやって｡
I'm using Mai-san's.
If you want to show off, try someone else.
What is it? More trouble?
厄介[やっかい]:trouble/burden|care, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
[℡]なに また厄介ごと？
双葉の中で
Am I nothing but trouble in your mind?
イコール:equal, 厄介[やっかい]:trouble/burden|care
僕ｲｺｰﾙ厄介ごとなのか｡
咲太 あれ｡
Look, Sakuta.
Azusagawa? What's wrong?
[℡]梓川 どうかした？
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 充電[じゅうでん]:charging (electrically)|electrification, 切れる[きれる]:to break|to be injured|to wear out||, っぽい:-ish/-like|tossing something out, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|
悪い なんか充電切れっぽいから
また連絡する｡
Sorry, battery's running out. I'll call back.
ちょっと待て！
Wait a sec!
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.)
電話の相手は私？
ああ｡
Were you talking to me on the phone?
Yeah.
ごまかし:hanky-panky/juggling/cheating
なら ごまかしは
きかないだろうね｡
Then I guess there's no hiding it.
どういう:somehow/how/in what way
私が２人いるんだ｡
それ どういうことだ？
There are two of me.
What's that supposed to mean?
とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light), 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|
言ったとおり ３日前から
この世界には
Exactly what I said.
There have been two Futaba Rios
since three days ago.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉理央が２人いる｡
Is it Puberty Syndrome?
思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome, 認める[したためる]:to write up, 認める[みとめる]:to recognize|to deem|to approve||
思春期症候群ってこと？
認めたくないですけど…｡
As much as I hate to admit it.
Any idea what caused it?
心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea, とっく:a long time ago|quickly/swiftly, とっく:special ward|special economic zone (China), 対処[たいしょ]:dealing with/coping with
心当たりは？
あれば とっくに対処してる｡
If I did, I would've dealt with it by now.
昼[ひる]:noon|daytime|lunch, 本屋[ほんおく]:principal residence, 本屋[ほんや]:bookstore|publisher|main building, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried
僕が昼に本屋で会ったのは
もう一人のほうか？
The one I met at the bookstore this afternoon was your counterpart, huh?
私は梓川に会ってないから
そういうことだろうね｡
I hadn't seen you today, so it must've been.
偽者[にせもの]:impostor/imposter/pretender, 迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance
あの偽者には迷惑してる｡
That impostor is a pain in the ass.
家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 居座る[いすわる]:to remain/to stay (somewhere), 生活[せいかつ]:living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood, おかげ:grace (of God)/benevolence (of Buddha)|assistance
家に居座って
生活してくれてるおかげで
Since she's squatting at my place and going about her life, I can't even go home.
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
私は帰るに帰れない｡
So you went to a net café?
ネットカフェ:Internet cafe/net cafe, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, よこす:to send/to forward|to hand over (e.g. money)
それでﾈｯﾄｶﾌｪかよ｡
さっさと僕に連絡よこせって｡
You should've contacted me first.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 泊める[とめる]:to give shelter to/to lodge/to put up
麻衣さん 今日から 双葉を
うちに泊めますけど
Mai-san, I'm going to have Futaba
stay over at my place. That's okay, right?
いいですよね？
ﾀﾞﾒよ｡
え？
Nope.
Huh? But Futaba's my friend.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
だって 双葉は友達ですよ？
だったら聞くけど
Then let me ask you this:
家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 男友達[おとこともだち]:boyfriend/man friend, 泊める[とめる]:to give shelter to/to lodge/to put up
私が家に男友達を泊めるって
言ったら 咲太はOKする？
if I said I was going to let a male friend
stay with me, would you be okay with it?
想像[そうぞう]:imagination/guess, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
あっ… 想像するのも嫌です｡
でしょ？
I don't even want to imagine that.
Right?
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
だから 私も一緒に泊まる｡
So I'm going to stay over too.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 新しい[あたらしい]:new/novel/fresh, 連れる[つれる]:to lead/to take (a person)
お兄ちゃんが また新しい女の人を
連れてきました｡
Onii-chan brought home yet another girl.
人聞き[ひとぎき]:reputation/respectability, 悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing, 妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend
人聞きが悪いな｡
で でも かえでは妹なので
Don't make me sound like a playboy.
B-But I'm your little sister, so I'll accept everything about you, flaws and all!
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 受け入れる[うけいれる]:to accept/to receive/to agree, 覚悟[かくご]:resolution/resignation/readiness
そんなお兄ちゃんも
受け入れる覚悟です｡
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, よろしく:well/properly|best regards
彼女は 友達の双葉理央｡
よろしく｡
This is Futaba Rio, my friend.
Nice to meet you.
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
あ 梓川かえでです…｡
I-I'm Azusagawa Kaede.
This is Nasuno,
この子は なすの｡
and this one is Hayate.
はやて:gale/strong wind/swift wind
こっちの子は はやてです｡
(鳴き声)
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 泊まる[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
２人とも 今日から しばらく
うちに泊まるから｡
They'll both be staying with us for a while.
えっと:let me see/well/errr ..., 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable, 寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||
えっと 麻衣さんと双葉は
僕の部屋で寝て 僕は…｡
Uh...
Mai-san and Futaba can sleep in my room, and I'll...
You can sleep with me in my room, then!
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), 部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
それじゃ お兄ちゃんは
かえでの部屋で一緒に！
Motion denied. I'll sleep in the living room.
却下[きゃっか]:rejection/dismissal, リビング:living/lifestyle, 寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||
却下 僕はﾘﾋﾞﾝｸﾞで寝る｡
I'm going to go home and pick up some clothes.
いったん:once|for a short time/briefly, いったん:one end/an end|part, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from, 着替える[きがえる, きかえる]:to change one's clothes, とってくる:to fetch/to go and get
私 いったん家に戻って
着替えとってくる｡
風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion, 済む[すむ]:to finish|to merely result in something less severe than expected|to feel at ease|
お風呂も ついでに
済ませてくるから｡
I'll take a bath while I'm there, too.
You can go ahead and take a bath, then, Futaba.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, 先[さき]:previous|point (e.g. pencil)|head (of a line)||, 先[せん]:former/previous|first move (in go, shogi, etc.)
じゃあ 双葉 風呂 先にいいぞ｡
Just so we're clear, I'm not gonna do anything with your bath soup.
ハッキリ:clearly/plainly/distinctly, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, 湯[ゆ]:hot water|hot bath|molten iron, 湯[タン]:soup
ﾊｯｷﾘ言っとくが 双葉でﾀﾞｼとった
風呂のお湯で
どうこう:trend/tendency/movement, どうこう:similar tastes
どうこうするつもりはないからな｡
Azusagawa...
梓川…｡
わかってくれたか？
Understand?
You needed to die the moment you said the words "bath soup."
時点[じてん]:point in time/occasion
ﾀﾞｼとか言ってる時点で死ね｡
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
I'll leave a towel here.
タオル:towel, 置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||
ﾀｵﾙ 置いておくな｡
うん｡
Okay.
着替え[きがえ]:changing clothes/change of clothes
着替えはあるんだっけ？
あるよ｡
Do you have a change of clothes?
I do.
If you don't, you can borrow a
bunny-girl outfit or panda pajamas.
バニーガール:bunny girl, 衣装[いしょう]:clothing/costume/outfit, パンダ:panda, パジャマ:pajamas/pyjamas, 貸す[かす]:to lend/to loan|to rent out
なければ ﾊﾞﾆｰｶﾞｰﾙの衣装か
ﾊﾟﾝﾀﾞのﾊﾟｼﾞｬﾏ貸すぞ｡
今 あるって言った｡
それはそうと 大丈夫か？
I just said I do.
That aside, you okay?
梓川が そこからいなくなればね｡
I will be once you go away.
よっこいしょ:(expression of) effort or strain/heave-ho
よっこいしょ…｡
Hup.
風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, 外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 落ち着く[おちつく]:to calm down|to calm down|to settle down (in a location, job, etc.)||
どうして 風呂の外で落ち着く？
Why would you make yourself comfortable outside the bath?
That "you okay" question was about your Puberty Syndrome.
思春期[ししゅんき]:puberty, 症候群[しょうこうぐん]:syndrome
今の ｢大丈夫か？｣は
思春期症候群についてな｡
よくわからない…｡
I don't really know.
Is that all?
それだけか？
何て言わせたいの？
What do you want me to say?
Nothing. I just want to hear what you think.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 感想[かんそう]:impressions/thoughts
べつに
双葉の感想を聞きたいだけ｡
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
少し怖い…｡
I'm a little scared.
Just a little, huh?
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, ネットカフェ:Internet cafe/net cafe
少しだけか｡
ﾈｯﾄｶﾌｪに１人のときは
I was really scared when I was alone at the net café.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
すごく怖かった｡
けどさ
But, hey, how is this even possible?
こんなことってありえるのか？
How can there be two of one person?
存在[そんざい]:existence/being, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
１人の人間が
２人存在するなんて｡
If quantum teleportation happens
on the macro level, then it is possible.
マクロ:macro, 世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 量子[りょうし]:quantum, テレポーテーション:teleportation, 成立[せいりつ]:coming into existence/arrangements|to come into existence
ﾏｸﾛの世界で 量子ﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾃｰｼｮﾝが
成立するなら
可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility
可能性はあるかもね｡
Teleportation? That only happens in movies.
テレポーテーション:teleportation, 映画[えいが]:movie/film, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
ﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾃｰｼｮﾝ？
映画の話だろ それ｡
現実[げんじつ]:reality/actuality/hard fact, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
そうでもないよ 現実の話｡
ﾏｼﾞか!?
You'd be surprised. It's very real.
Seriously?
Remember how we talked
about quantum entanglement?
量子[りょうし]:quantum, もつれ:tangle/entanglement|complication, 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
前に 量子もつれの話はしたよね｡
今回[こんかい]:now/this time/lately, 件[くだん]:the aforementioned/the said|the usual, 件[けん]:matter/case/item, 当てはめる[あてはめる]:to apply/to adapt, 簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief, 説明[せつめい]:explanation/exposition
今回の件に当てはめて
簡単に説明すると
If I were to apply the theory here and explain it in simple terms...
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 構築[こうちく]:construction/building/putting up, 情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information
例えば 私を構築している情報の
Let's say there's a framework of all my information, my blueprints.
設計図[せっけいず]:plan/blueprint, 簡単[かんたん]:simple/easy|brief
設計図があるとするでしょ？
それ簡単か？
How is that simple?
情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information, 量子[りょうし]:quantum, もつれ:tangle/entanglement|complication, 利用[りよう]:use/utilization/utilisation
その情報を
量子もつれを利用して
And that info is sent instantly,
via quantum entanglement, to a distant location.
離れる[はなれる]:to be separated|to leave|to leave (a job, etc.)|, 位置[いち]:place/situation/position, 一瞬[いっしゅん]:instant/moment/for an instant, 移動[いどう]:movement/transfer|mobile, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
離れた位置に
一瞬で移動させたとする｡
Like sending the info of you here, in our bath, to the school?
例えば[たとえば]:for example/for instance/e.g., 風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information
例えば うちの風呂にいる
双葉の情報を
学校[がっこう]:school, 飛ばす[とばす]:to fly|to skip over|to run or drive fast||
学校に飛ばしたとか？
そう｡
Right.
学校[がっこう]:school, 構築[こうちく]:construction/building/putting up, 情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information
学校にある私を構築する情報は
And if my information framework in school
観測[かんそく]:observation/survey/measurement, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 姿[すがた]:figure|appearance|state||, 確定[かくてい]:decision/settlement|definition
誰かに観測されることで
双葉理央の姿に確定される｡
is observed by someone,
it will be recognized as Futaba Rio.
理屈[りくつ]:theory/reason, 同時[どうじ]:simultaneous/concurrent/same time, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being
その理屈だと
同時に２人が存在するのは
Going by that logic, wouldn't it be impossible for two of you to exist at once?
無理[むり]:unreasonable|impossible|forcible||, とおり:avenue/street|coming and going, とおり:penetration (as of light)
無理なんじゃないのか？
そのとおりだよ｡
That's right.
実[じつ, じち]:truth|sincerity|content|, 実[み]:fruit|seed|(in broth) pieces of meat, vegetable, etc.|, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried
実は私は もう一人の自分を
見たわけじゃないんだ｡
The thing is, I haven't actually seen my other self.
同時[どうじ]:simultaneous/concurrent/same time, 存在[そんざい]:existence/being
だから 同時に存在しているのかと
聞かれると
So I can't say for sure that we both exist at the same time.
言い切る[いいきる]:to declare/to assert|to finish saying
そうだとは言い切れない｡
But when I saw you at the net café,
I was talking to the other one over the phone.
ネットカフェ:Internet cafe/net cafe
けど ﾈｯﾄｶﾌｪで会ったとき
スマホ:smartphone/smart phone, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), してい:servant/janitor/messenger, してい:older sister and younger brother
僕はｽﾏﾎで もう一人の双葉と
電話をしていた｡
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), ホント:truth/reality/actuality
電話の相手は ﾎﾝﾄに私だった？
見たわけじゃないからな｡
Was it really me on the other end?
Well, I didn't see her.
量子[りょうし]:quantum, テレポーテーション:teleportation
あっ でも 量子ﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾃｰｼｮﾝ？
Oh, but what was it, quantum teleportation?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 構築[こうちく]:construction/building/putting up, 情報[じょうほう]:information/news|information, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
双葉を構築する情報ってのが
同じなら
If both your information frameworks are the same,
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 観測[かんそく]:observation/survey/measurement, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
どっちで観測されたとしても
wouldn't your awareness and memories be synced, no matter which of you observed it?
意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 記憶[きおく]:memory/recollection|storage, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
意識や記憶は
一緒なんじゃないのか？
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 観測[かんそく]:observation/survey/measurement, 私自身[わたしじしん, わたくしじしん]:myself, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful
私 双葉理央を観測しているのが
私自身だったとして
Let's say that I, Futaba Rio,
am being observed by myself.
観測[かんそく]:observation/survey/measurement, 意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
私を観測する私の意識が
なんらかの理由で
Now, what if there were two of the consciousness observing me for some reason?
存在[そんざい]:existence/being
２つ存在しているのだとしたら
It might result in something like this current scenario.
状態[じょうたい]:current status/condition/situation, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
今のような状態に
なるのかもしれない｡
You mean, like, two personas?
人格[じんかく]:personality/character/individuality
それって 人格が
２つあるってことか｡
仮[け]:lacking substance and existing in name only/something without substance, 仮[かり]:temporary|fictitious|hypothetical, たとする:to appreciate/to be thankful, ことになる:it has been decided (so) that/it has been arranged (so) that|it is the result (of)
仮に そうだったとして
どうして そんなことになった？
Even if that were true, why would there be two to begin with?
心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea
心当たりはないって言ったでしょ｡
Didn't I tell you I have no idea?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
麻衣さん｡
ん？
Mai-san?
顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
何してんの？
咲太の顔を見てる｡
What are you doing?
Staring at your face.
Uh, yeah, that I can tell.
いや そうなんだけど…｡
I'm staring at my boyfriend's face.
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
彼氏の顔を見てる｡
ﾄﾞｷｯとしたでしょ？
Heart skipped a beat, didn't it?
You're enjoying this, huh?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 浮かれる[うかれる]:to make merry/to be festive
麻衣さん 浮かれてる？
Of course. I finally get to spend time with my boyfriend and stay over at his place.
久しぶり[ひさしぶり]:a long time (since the last time)/it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you), 彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, ゆっくり:slowly/at ease/restful, 会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association, 泊る[とまる]:to stay at (e.g. hotel)|to be docked/to be berthed
久しぶりに彼氏とゆっくり会えて
お泊りしてるんだから
当たり前[あたりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
当たり前でしょ｡
双葉は？
What about Futaba?
ぐっすり:sound asleep/fast asleep, 眠る[ねむる, ねぶる]:to sleep (not necessarily lying down)|to die|to lie idle (e.g. of resources)|
ぐっすり眠ってる｡
Out like a light.
She probably hasn't slept in peace for days.
何日[なんにち]:what day|how many days, 安心[あんしん]:relief/peace of mind, 安心[あんじん]:obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice, 眠る[ねむる, ねぶる]:to sleep (not necessarily lying down)|to die|to lie idle (e.g. of resources)|
この何日か 安心して
眠れなかったんじゃない？
そうですか…｡
咲太は 目の前にいる私より
I see...
You're more concerned with Futaba-san when I'm right here?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 気になる[きになる]:to be on one's mind|to feel like|to fancy
双葉さんが気になるんだ｡
Aw...
明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 一日[いちにち, いちじつ]:one day|first day of the month, 一日[つきたち]:first day of the month|first ten days of the lunar month
あ～あ 明日
一日ｵﾌになったから
I thought I could go on a date with you tomorrow since I have the whole day off.
デート:date/go on a date, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
ﾃﾞｰﾄしてあげようと思ってたのに｡
Why are you making it sound like it's not happening?
風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold
どうしてﾀﾞﾒになった風なんですか｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 調べる[しらべる]:to examine/to investigate/to check up
だって咲太は 双葉さんのこと
調べるつもりでしょ｡
I mean, you're going to look into Futaba-san's situation, right?
偽者[にせもの]:impostor/imposter/pretender, 科学[かがく]:science, 部[ぶ]:department (in an organization)|club|part||, 活動[かつどう]:action/activity|movie (esp. during the silent movie period), 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 学校[がっこう]:school
偽者は科学部の活動で
明日も学校だと思うので
The fake will probably be back at school tomorrow for science club stuff,
様子[ようす]:state|appearance|sign
まあ 様子を見に行こうとは
思ってました｡
so yeah, I was thinking of going to check on her.
See? I knew it.
やっぱり:too/also|still, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
ほら やっぱり｡
そこで麻衣さんにお願いが｡
On that note, I need a favor from you.
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant, どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 偽者[にせもの]:impostor/imposter/pretender, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
嫌｡ どうせ咲太が
偽者のところに行ってる間
No.
I bet you want me to watch over Futaba-san while you're with the fake.
本物[ほんもの]:genuine article/real thing/real deal, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
本物の双葉さんが どうしてるか
私に見ておけって言うんでしょ？
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
さすが麻衣さん
僕のこと よくわかってる｡
That's my Mai-san. You know me very well.
Don't be happy about that.
喜ぶ[よろこぶ]:to be delighted|to congratulate|to gratefully accept, 痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding
喜ぶな｡
痛い 痛い…｡
Ow. You're hurting me.
Don't be happy about that either.
喜ぶ[よろこぶ]:to be delighted|to congratulate|to gratefully accept
喜ぶな｡
というわけなんで
So yeah, please.
願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
お願いします｡
仕事[しごと]:work/job|work, 忙しい[いそがしい, せわしい]:busy/occupied|restless, ほったらかしにする:to neglect/to let alone, 詫び[わび]:apology/excuse
じゃあ 仕事が忙しくて
ほったらかしにしたお詫びは
With this, we'll be even for my
neglecting you over work, right?
チャラ:forgiving a debt/getting even, 詫び[わび]:apology/excuse
ﾁｬﾗでいいわね｡
え～ お詫びはお詫びでほしいな｡
What? I need a proper token of apology!
Hey, I'm sleeping next to you right now.
添い寝[そいね]:sleeping together, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
今 添い寝してあげてる｡
I was hoping for something
that rhymes with "amiss."
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, ねずみ:mouse/rat|dark gray, 鳴き声[なきごえ]:cry (esp. animal)/roar/chirp, 的[てき]:-like/typical, 的[まと]:mark/target
もっとこう ねずみの鳴き声的な｡
あれ わかりませんでした？
Huh? Was that too obtuse?
You don't have use an apology as an excuse.
詫び[わび]:apology/excuse, 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
べつに
お詫びを理由にしなくても
場所[ばしょ]:place|room|basho, 雰囲気[ふんいき, ふいんき]:mood|a certain air|air, ちゃんと:diligently/seriously|perfectly, 選ぶ[えらぶ]:to choose/to select
時と場所と雰囲気を
ちゃんと選んでくれれば
So long as you pick the right time, place, and mood,
咲太のほうから
してくれてもいいのよ｡
I don't mind you taking the initiative, you know?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
麻衣さん…｡
何よ？
Mai-san...
What?
That hurt.
痛い[いたい]:painful/sore|exceeding, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 恥ずかしい[はずかしい]:shy/ashamed|disgraceful
痛いわね｡
麻衣さんが恥ずかしがって
It's because you got shy and tilted your head.
うつむく:to hang one's head/to look down/to cast one's eyes downward, がっつく:to be greedy/to devour greedily
うつむくから｡
咲太が がっつくからよ｡
No, you went in too hard.
Mai-san?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
麻衣さん？
We're done for tonight.
おしまい:the end/closing|That's it
今日は もうおしまい｡
え～｡
Blame yourself for sucking.
ヘタクソ:shitty/clumsy/poor, 傷つく[きずつく]:to be wounded|to get hurt feelings|to get damaged
咲太がﾍﾀｸｿだからじゃない｡
うわぁ それ傷つくなぁ｡
Wow, that hurts.
自信[じしん]:self-confidence/confidence (in oneself), 女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 恐怖症[きょうふしょう]:morbid fear/phobia
自信なくして
女性恐怖症になりそう｡
I might lose all confidence and gain a fear of women.
そんなことにはならないわよ｡
その心は？
That won't happen.
What makes you so sure?
上手[じょうず, じょうて]:skill/skillful|flattery, 上手[うわて, かみて]:upper part|upper stream|right side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV)||
上手にできるようになるまで
Because I'll let you practice as many times as you want until you can do it right.
何度[なんど]:how many times?/how often?, 練習[れんしゅう]:practice/practising, あげる:to raise/to elevate|to do up (one's hair)
私が 何度でも
練習させてあげるから｡
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
麻衣さん…｡
何よ？
Mai-san...
What?
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
すげえ好きです｡
知ってる｡
I love you with all my heart.
I know.
おやすみ:holiday/day off|sleep, おやすみなさい:good night
じゃ おやすみ｡
はい おやすみなさい｡
Good night, then.
Yeah. Good night.
August 3rd
Onii-chan, this is yummy! It's so soft!
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, おいしい:delicious/tasty|attractive, フワフワ:lightly (floating, drifting, etc.)/buoyantly
お兄ちゃん これ おいしいです！
ﾌﾜﾌﾜしてます｡
The egg's great too.
玉子[たまご]:eggs|hen egg|(an expert) in the making|, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
玉子もうまいぞ｡
And this melts in my mouth!
こっちはﾄﾛﾄﾛしてます｡
Let's have Mai-san cook for us
every day from now on.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 毎日[まいにち]:every day, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
これから 麻衣さんに
毎日 作ってもらおうな｡
Yeah!
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
はい！
かえでちゃんを
Don't use Kaede-chan as an excuse.
利用[りよう]:use/utilization/utilisation
利用するんじゃないの！
ｲｯ！
What's the matter, Onii-chan?
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 愛[あい]:love/affection|attachment, 愛[まな]:beloved/dear, 試す[ためす]:to attempt/to test/to try out
どうしたんですか？ お兄ちゃん｡
愛を試されてるんだ｡
My love's being put to the test.
You don't like it, Futaba-san?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 口に合う[くちにあう]:to be palatable/to suit one's taste
双葉さん 口に合わない？
あっ いえ
Oh, it's not that.
朝食[ちょうしょく, あさげ]:breakfast, 久しぶり[ひさしぶり]:a long time (since the last time)/it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)
誰かとの朝食が
久しぶりだったので｡
It's just been a while since the last time
I wasn't alone for breakfast.
Good morning, Sakuta-san.
おはようございます:good morning
おはようございます 咲太さん｡
Morning.
おはよう:good morning
おはよう｡
あっ…｡
お客様[おきゃくさま]:guest/visitor|customer, いろいろ:various|various colors (colours)
お客様ですか？
ちょっといろいろあってね｡
Do you have visitors?
It's a long story.
あがる:to rise/to go up|to enter (esp. from outdoors), あがる:to win a hand
大丈夫だから あがって｡
But don't worry about that. Come on in.
Oh, morning, Shouko-chan.
おはよう:good morning, おはようございます:good morning
あっ おはよう 翔子ちゃん｡
おはようございます｡
Good morning.
女性[じょせい, にょしょう]:woman/female|feminine gender, 知り合い[しりあい]:acquaintance
咲太さんは 女性のお知り合いが
多いんですね｡
You have a lot of female friends, Sakuta-san.
他意[たい]:ill will/malice/another intention
あ…｡
あっ 他意はありません｡
Oh, I didn't mean anything by that.
She's Futaba Rio, a friend from school.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school, 同級生[どうきゅうせい]:classmate
彼女は 双葉理央
高校の同級生｡
牧之原翔子といいます｡
My name is Makinohara Shouko.
She's real, huh?
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 実在[じつざい]:reality/existence
ﾎﾝﾄに実在したんだ…｡
Futaba, you in?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉 いるか？
練習[れんしゅう]:practice/practising, 試合[しあい]:match/game/bout
そういや 国見が
練習試合やってるって言ってたな｡
Come to think of it, Kunimi said he had a practice game.
Suimei U Prep
Minegahara High
There she is.
いるな｡
年生[ねんせい]:pupil in ... year/student in ... year
あれ ３年生かな？
Is that a third-year?
She looks kinda sexy. Sexy and smart.
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, 賢い[かしこい]:wise/clever/smart
なんかｴﾛい ｴﾛ賢い｡
Is Kunimi balling out?
活躍[かつやく]:activity (esp. energetic)/great efforts|to flourish
国見は活躍してんのか？
I just came to take a peek while I was here for club.
部活[ぶかつ]:club activities, ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion
部活のついでに
見に来ただけだから｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, キャー:yikes!/eek!/ouch!
双葉も ｢ｷｬｰ 国見！｣とか
やったら？
Why don't you join the others and go, "Ohmigosh! Kunimi!"?
I'm rooting for him too.
応援[おうえん]:aid/assistance/help
応援ならしてる｡
心の中で？
On the inside?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, アピール:appeal (e.g. to public opinion)/plea/request, 不足[ふそく]:insufficiency/shortage/deficiency, 邪魔[じゃま]:hindrance|to visit (somebody's home)|demon who hinders Buddhist training
双葉はｱﾋﾟｰﾙ不足なんだよ｡
邪魔しないでほしいんだけど｡
You're not doing enough to appeal to him.
Could you stop bothering me?
Suimei U Prep
Minegahara High
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 惚れる[ほれる]:to fall in love/to be in love/to be charmed with
で 結局 双葉は
国見のどこに惚れたわけ？
Y'know, all said and done,
what about Kunimi made you fall for him?
知ってどうするの？
べつに どうも｡
Why do you want to know?
No reason, really. Just curious.
単なる[たんなる]:mere/simple/sheer, 興味[きょうみ]:interest (in something)/curiosity (about something)/zest (for)
単なる興味｡
ﾊｧ…｡
Chocolate cornet.
チョコ:chocolate, ダッシュ:dash, 買う[かう]:to buy|to value|to stir
ﾁｮｺｺﾛﾈ｡
ﾀﾞｯｼｭで買ってこいと？
Buy you one on the double?
No.
お弁当[おべんとう]:bento/Japanese box lunch, 持つ[もつ]:to hold (in one's hand)|to possess|to maintain||
違う｡
お弁当を持ってこなかった日に
When I didn't bring lunch one day,
Kunimi let me have his.
国見がくれた｡
It was during our first term here.
学期[がっき]:school term/semester, 販売[はんばい, ハンバイ]:sales/selling/marketing, 利用[りよう]:use/utilization/utilisation
１年の１学期で
ﾊﾟﾝ販売を利用するのは
That was the first time I'd had to visit the school shop.
初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
あの日が初めてで…｡
I gave up and was walking away when Kunimi talked to me.
圧倒[あっとう]:overwhelm/overpower/overwhelming, 声をかける[こえをかける]:to greet/to call out to someone
圧倒されている私に
国見が声をかけてきた｡
You're a girl, Futaba. You like sweet stuff, don't you?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 甘い[あまい]:sweet-tasting|fragrant (smelling)|lightly salted||, 甘い[うまい]:skillful|delicious|fortunate, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
⦅双葉は女子だから
甘いものが好きだよな⦆
He said that while eating his prized curry bun.
戦利品[せんりひん]:spoils of war/booty, カレーパン:curry bread (usu. deep-fried)/curry doughnut/curry bun, 食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off, ながら:while/during|while
(理央)戦利品のｶﾚｰﾊﾟﾝを
食べながら｡
The Curry Bun Prince, huh?
カレーパン:curry bread (usu. deep-fried)/curry doughnut/curry bun, 王子[おうじ]:prince|subordinate Kumano shrine, 様[ざま]:mess|-ways|in the act of ...|, 様[さま]:Mr.|makes words more polite (usu. in fixed expressions)|state
ｶﾚｰﾊﾟﾝの王子様だな｡
それで？
それだけ｡
And?
That's it.
チョコ:chocolate, いくら:how much?/how many?|even, 円[えん]:yen/Japanese monetary unit|circle, 円[まる]:circle|entirety|money||
ﾁｮｺｺﾛﾈって いくら？
130円｡
How much is a chocolate cornet?
130 yen.
Your love doesn't cost much, huh?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 手軽[てがる]:easy/simple/informal
双葉って お手軽なのな｡
I wouldn't have fallen for you in that situation.
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
相手が梓川だったら
好きになってなかった｡
So in the end, it's all about looks?
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 顔[かお, がん]:face|look|honor|, 顔[かんばせ]:countenance/visage|face
結局 顔かよ｡
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, タイミング:timing
結局 ﾀｲﾐﾝｸﾞだと思う｡
I think it was all about the timing.
I was really down in the dumps back then.
頃[ころ, ごろ]:(approximate) time|suitable time (or condition)|time of year, 頃[けい]:qing (Chinese unit of land area equal to 100 mu), 気分[きぶん]:feeling/mood, 落ちる[おちる]:to fall down|to be omitted|to decrease||
あの頃 気分が落ちてたから｡
If you want to stare, just do it.
見たけりゃ 見ればいいのに｡
A-Anyway, what do you want?
用[よう]:business|use|for the use of ...|
それで 梓川は何の用？
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
今さ うちに双葉がいるんだよ｡
Futaba's at my place right now.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 様子[ようす]:state|appearance|sign, おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
なるほど 昨日の夜
電話の様子がおかしかったのは
I see. So that's why you sounded off
on the phone last night.
起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
そのせい｡
これって
何が起きてるんだろうな｡
What's going on here?
偽者[にせもの]:impostor/imposter/pretender
私のこと 偽者だと思ってる？
Do you think I'm a fake?
正直[しょうじき]:honesty/integrity|honestly, 最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first
正直 最初は そう思ってた｡
Honestly, I did at first.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
けど こうして話してると
どっちも双葉だ｡
But after talking to you like this,
I realize you're both Futaba.
What does my other self think?
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 見解[けんかい]:opinion/point of view
もう一人の私の見解は？
可能性[かのうせい]:potentiality/likelihood/possibility, 量子[りょうし]:quantum, テレポーテーション:teleportation
可能性があるとすれば
量子ﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾃｰｼｮﾝだとか｡
She said the only thing she could think of
was quantum teleportation.
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 考え[かんがえ]:thinking|idea|intention||
私と同じ考えだね｡
Same as me, huh?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 観測[かんそく]:observation/survey/measurement, 意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information)
双葉を観測しているのは
双葉の意識そのもので
You're being observed by
your own consciousness,
意識[いしき]:consciousness|awareness|mano-vijnana (mental consciousness, cognizer of sensory information), 理由[りゆう, わけ]:reason/pretext/motive
その意識がなんらかの理由で
and for some reason, there are two of those, was the assumption.
存在[そんざい]:existence/being, 考察[こうさつ]:consideration/inquiry/enquiry
２つ存在しているんじゃないか
って考察だったな｡
原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source, 心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea
原因については？
心当たりはないってさ｡
What about the cause?
She said she had no idea.
And you believed her lie?
信ずる[しんずる]:to believe/to believe in/to place trust in
そんなｳｿを梓川は信じたわけ？
なんで ｳｿだと思う？
What makes you think she was lying?
心当たりがある[こころあたりがある]:to have an idea/to have a clue
私には心当たりがあるから｡
Because I have a very good idea of what caused it.
If it doesn't matter which one I ask,
why don't you tell me?
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach
どっちに聞いても同じなら
教えてくれ｡
部活[ぶかつ]:club activities, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
私 部活に戻るから｡
I'm going back to club.
カッコ:parentheses/brackets, カッコ:shape/form/figure
このＸとＹはｶｯｺの中だから…｡
X and Y here are inside the parentheses...
Right.
コーヒー:coffee, 淹れる[いれる]:to make (tea, coffee, etc.)/to brew a beverage (with hot water), 飲む[のむ]:to drink|to smoke (tobacco)|to engulf||
はい｡
ｺｰﾋｰ淹れるけど 飲む？
I'm making coffee. Want some?
Y-Yes, please.
あっ はい どうも｡
I'm the little sister,
妹[いもうと]:younger sister, 妹[いも]:darling (only of a woman)|one's sister|friend, ミルク:milk, ハチミツ:honey, たっぷり:full/in plenty/ample
かえでは妹なので
ﾐﾙｸとﾊﾁﾐﾂたっぷりの
so my favorite is café au lait
with lots of milk and honey!
ハニー:honey, カフェオレ:café au lait, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
ﾊﾆｰｶﾌｪｵﾚが好きです｡
I'd love to have that as well.
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, いただける:to be able to receive/to be able to take|to be able to eat, うれしい:happy/glad/pleasant
私も かえでちゃんと同じものを
いただけると うれしいです｡
じゃあ 私もそうしようかな｡
[℡]
Maybe I'll go with that too.
かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.), マネージャー:manager (e.g. of a business, an idol, etc.)
あっ ごめん かえでちゃん
ﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰからみたい｡
Sorry, Kaede-chan!
Looks like it's my manager.
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
どうかしたんですか？
[℡]今 お電話は？
Is something the matter?
Are you free to talk?
Sure.
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 撮影[さつえい]:photography (still or motion)/photographing/filming, お疲れさま[おつかれさま]:thank you/many thanks|that's enough for today
大丈夫です｡
[℡]昨日まで撮影お疲れさまでした｡
Great work with the shoot.
Are you out right now?
もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance, 外[そと, と]:outside|open air|other place, 外[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family
[℡]もしかして 今 外ですか？
はい 彼氏の家です｡
Yeah, I'm over at my boyfriend's place.
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend
[℡]あ～ 彼氏… って えっ!?
Oh, your boyfriend...
Wait, boyfriend? Did you just say "boyfriend"?!
彼氏[かれし]:boyfriend
[℡]彼氏!?
今 彼氏って言いました？
Wasn't Futaba here until a moment ago?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 気づく[きづく]:to notice/to recognize/to recognise
双葉 さっきまでいたよな｡
気づいてたのかよ｡
You noticed?
Soon after the game started.
試合[しあい]:match/game/bout, 始まる[はじまる]:to begin|to happen (again)|to date (from), 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
試合が始まって すぐ｡
双葉って よく来るのか？
Does she come to watch often?
科学[かがく]:science, 部[ぶ]:department (in an organization)|club|part||, ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion, たまに:occasionally/once in a while, 感じ[かんじ]:feeling/sense/impression
ん～ どうだろ 科学部のついでに
たまにって感じ？
Hmm, dunno. Feels like she drops by every now and then while she's here for club.
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), ついで:next/secondly/subsequently, ついで:opportunity/occasion, もしかし:perhaps/maybe/by some chance
どっちが ついでなんだか｡
もしかして
I wonder which one has higher priority.
Did something happen to her?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉に何かあった？
何かって なんだよ？
What do you mean?
夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 登校[とうこう]:attendance (at school)/going to school
咲太は 夏休みに
登校してくるほど
I know you don't like school enough to come in during summer break.
学校[がっこう]:school, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to), 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
学校が好きじゃないだろ？
となると 双葉に
So I figured maybe something happened to her.
何かあったのかなって｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, コーチ:coach, 呼ぶ[よぶ]:to call out (to)|to summon (a doctor, etc.)|to invite||
≪国見先輩 ｺｰﾁが呼んでます｡
わかった 今行く｡
Kunimi-senpai, the coach wants you.
Gotcha. Coming.
声[こえ]:voice, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
何かあったら 声かけろよ｡
ん？
Let me know if you need anything.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉のこと｡
言われなくても そのつもり｡
With Futaba.
I would have anyway. You'd better come flying even if I call you in the dead of night.
夜中[よなか]:middle of the night/dead of night, 夜中[やちゅう]:during the night/at night, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, 飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump, 空[から]:emptiness/vacuum/blank, 空[そら]:sky|weather|far-off place||
夜中に連絡しても飛んで来いよ｡
空は飛べそうにないから
I don't think I can fly for real, so I'll just make my bike fly.
チャリ:bicycle, 飛ばす[とばす]:to fly|to skip over|to run or drive fast||
ﾁｬﾘを飛ばして行くわ｡
[℡]はい 梓川です｡
Hello? This is Azusagawa.
Mai-san, could you say that one more time?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 一度[いちど, ひとたび]:once|temporarily|one degree, 願う[ねがう]:to desire|to beg|to have something done for oneself
麻衣さん それ
もう一度お願いします｡
Hello. This is Azusagawa.
はい 梓川です｡
Could you sound a little more like a newlywed?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 新妻[にいづま]:new wife, 風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold
[℡]もっと新妻風がいいな｡
I'm amazed you can get so excited over a phone greeting.
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device), 一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 本[もと]:origin|base|cause||, 本[ほん]:book|this|main||
電話一本で よくそこまで
はしゃげるわね｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 学校[がっこう]:school
[℡]そっちは どうだったの？
双葉 学校に来てました｡
How'd it go with you?
Futaba came to school.
ずっと:continuously in some state (for a long time, distance)/throughout|much (better, etc.)
そう こっちもずっといるわよ｡
I see. This one's been here the entire time.
Anyway, can you come home now?
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
[℡]それより もう帰ってこられる？
どうかしたんですか？
Is something the matter?
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, マネージャー:manager (e.g. of a business, an idol, etc.), 電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
[℡]さっきﾏﾈｰｼﾞｬｰから電話があって
ちょっとね｡
My manager called me earlier.
I need to talk to you about something.
話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
[℡]咲太に話したいことがあるの｡
僕に？
To me?
なに？
[℡]いえ なんでも｡
What's up?
Nothing. I'll talk to you later.
[℡]それじゃ あとで｡
You're friends with that girl, aren't you?
友達[ともだち]:friend/companion
(沙紀)梓川って あの女と
友達なのよね？
察する[さっする]:to guess/to sense|to sympathize with, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
あの女というのは 察するに
双葉のことか？
I suppose you're talking about Futaba.
Isn't she up to some pretty funny business?
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
なんかﾔﾊﾞいことしてない？
あの女｡
ヤバい:dangerous|awful|terrific
ﾔﾊﾞいこと？
これ
Funny business?
Here. Look at her secret account.
裏[うら]:bottom (or another side that is hidden from view)|rear|lining||
あの女の裏ｱｶ｡
Selfie 72
Selfie 71
Selfie 70
Selfie 69
That's my Onii-chan! A total pig!
Next Episode
#8: Let the Rain Wash Everything Anew